[
    {
        "question": "1. (201) Which section of the Operation and Service Instructions Manual contains instructions for uncrating, installing, and preparing equipment for initial operations?",
        "options": [
            "a. Section 1.",
            "b. Section 2.",
            "c. Section 3.",
            "d. Section 4."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Section 3."
    },
    {
        "question": "2. (201) Which section of the Operation and Service Instructions Manual contains step-by-step instructions for starting, operating, and stopping equipment?",
        "options": [
            "a. Section 1.",
            "b. Section 2.",
            "c. Section 3.",
            "d. Section 4."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Section 4."
    },
    {
        "question": "3. (202) Which time compliance technical order (TCTO) requires you to discontinue use of equipment until prescribed maintenance work is completed?",
        "options": [
            "a. Interim TCTOs.",
            "b. Record TCTOs.",
            "c. Urgent action TCTOs.",
            "d. Immediate action TCTOs."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Immediate action TCTOs."
    },
    {
        "question": "4. (202) The time compliance technical order (TCTO) that must be issued if the risk involved is tolerable only within definite time limits is the ",
        "options": [
            "a. record TCTO.",
            "b. interim TCTO.",
            "c. urgent action TCTO.",
            "d. immediate action TCTO."
        ],
        "correct": "c. urgent action TCTO."
    },
    {
        "question": "5. (203) What do all technical order (TO) indexes have as the first number? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Zero (0).",
            "b. One (1).",
            "c. Two (2).",
            "d. Three (3)."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Zero (0)."
    },
    {
        "question": "6. (204) What format is used to submit corrections to a technical order (TO)?",
        "options": [
            "a. TO 00-5-1, AF Technical Order System.",
            "b. TO 0-1-01, Numerical Index and Requirements Tables.",
            "c. AFTO Form 158, Technical Order Review Comment Sheet.",
            "d. AFTO Form 22, Technical Manual (TM) Change Recommendation and Reply."
        ],
        "correct": "d. AFTO Form 22, Technical Manual (TM) Change Recommendation and Reply."
    },
    {
        "question": "7. (204) Which technical order (TO) improvement recommendation requires action within 40 days of its receipt?",
        "options": [
            "a. Urgent.",
            "b. Routine.",
            "c. Time compliance.",
            "d. Emergency/critical hazard."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Urgent."
    },
    {
        "question": "8. (204) What type of technical order (TO) improvement recommendation is submitted if prescribed maintenance procedures reduce the operational life of equipment?",
        "options": [
            "a. Urgent.",
            "b. Routine.",
            "c. Emergency.",
            "d. Time compliance."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Routine."
    },
    {
        "question": "9. (205) How are Unified Criteria Facilities (UFC) organized?",
        "options": [
            "a. Units and Volumes.",
            "b. Chapters and Articles.",
            "c. Chapters and Volumes.",
            "d. Series and Sub-Categories."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Series and Sub-Categories."
    },
    {
        "question": "10. (205) What information is in Chapter 1 of a Unified Criteria Facilities (UFC)?",
        "options": [
            "a. General overview listing the purpose, scope, and references for the UFC.",
            "b. Table of contents.",
            "c. Foreword.",
            "d. Glossary."
        ],
        "correct": "a. General overview listing the purpose, scope, and references for the UFC."
    },
    {
        "question": "11. (206) Who publishes the National Electric Code? ",
        "options": [
            "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA).",
            "b. American National Standards Institute (ANSI).",
            "c. National Electrical Manufactures Association (NEMA).",
            "d. Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)."
        ],
        "correct": "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA)."
    },
    {
        "question": "12. (206) What publication number is the National Electric Code?",
        "options": [
            "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 70E.",
            "b. NFPA 72.",
            "c. NFPA 70B.",
            "d. NFPA 70."
        ],
        "correct": "d. NFPA 70."
    },
    {
        "question": "13. (206) What publication number is the Standard for Electrical Safety in the Workplace? ",
        "options": [
            "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 70E.",
            "b. NFPA 72.",
            "c. NFPA 70B.",
            "d. NFPA 70."
        ],
        "correct": "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 70E."
    },
    {
        "question": "14. (207) What number is the maximum ohmic reading for static grounds according to current Air Force directives? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 10.",
            "b. 1,000.",
            "c. 10,000.",
            "d. 100,000."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 10,000."
    },
    {
        "question": "15. (207) An equipment ground is a grounding system that ",
        "options": [
            "a. stabilizes voltage between two or more metallic objects.",
            "b. removes excess voltage from current carrying metallic objects.",
            "c. drains off static electricity before a sparking potential is reached.",
            "d. connects to earth all nonconcurrent carrying metal parts of an electrical wiring system."
        ],
        "correct": "d. connects to earth all nonconcurrent carrying metal parts of an electrical wiring system."
    },
    {
        "question": "16. (207) What maximum ground resistance is the value for an electrical system with a voltage of 600 volts alternating current (VAC) or less?",
        "options": [
            "a. 1 ohm.",
            "b. 5 ohms.",
            "c. 10 ohms.",
            "d. 25 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 25 ohms."
    },
    {
        "question": "17. (207) During which season could you expect to measure the lowest ground reading? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Fall.",
            "b. Spring.",
            "c. Summer.",
            "d. Winter."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Spring."
    },
    {
        "question": "18. (208) Which location is the correct location for grounding a system neutral? ",
        "options": [
            "b. Source side of service entrance.",
            "c. Load side of service entrance and outlets.",
            "d. Source side of service entrance and outlets."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Source side of service entrance."
    },
    {
        "question": "19. (208) A system neutral conductor is likely grounded improperly (grounded on the load side of the service entrance disconnect), if the ohmic value is less than ",
        "options": [
            "a. 10K.",
            "b. 20K.",
            "c. 30K.",
            "d. 40K."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 20K."
    },
    {
        "question": "20. (209) At what intervals should a wye-connected distribution system neutral be grounded? ",
        "options": [
            "a. At a distance not to exceed ¼ mile.",
            "b. At a distance not to exceed ½ mile.",
            "c. At a distance not to exceed 1 mile.",
            "d. This system neutral is not grounded."
        ],
        "correct": "a. At a distance not to exceed ¼ mile."
    },
    {
        "question": "21. (209) What recommended depth is the top of a ground rod driven for distribution pole grounding? ",
        "options": [
            "a. At ground level.",
            "b. Below ground level.",
            "c. 1 foot above ground level.",
            "d. 2 feet below ground level."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 2 feet below ground level."
    },
    {
        "question": "22. (210) The metal frame of a building can be used as a facility ground ",
        "options": [
            "a. if the frame is effectively grounded.",
            "b. if the building is equipped with air terminals.",
            "c. only when it is supported by insulated flanges.",
            "d. only if the braces are separately bonded to the ground loop."
        ],
        "correct": "a. if the frame is effectively grounded."
    },
    {
        "question": "23. (210) What are the requirements for a facility ground rod? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 4 feet long; copper-clad steel, solid copper, or galvanized steel.",
            "b. 8 feet long; copper-clad steel, solid copper, or galvanized steel.",
            "c. 4 feet long; copper-clad steel, solid copper, or stainless steel.",
            "d. 8 feet long; copper-clad steel, solid copper, or stainless steel."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 8 feet long; copper-clad steel, solid copper, or stainless steel."
    },
    {
        "question": "24. (210) Which is the minimum allowed resistance for an electrode used for communications network grounds? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 25 ohms.",
            "b. 20 ohms.",
            "c. 10 ohms.",
            "d. 5 ohms."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 10 ohms."
    },
    {
        "question": "25. (210) Isolated ground (IG) receptacles are used in circuits feeding electronic devices to ",
        "options": [
            "a. minimize noise.",
            "b. filter voltage spikes.",
            "c. stabilize current draw.",
            "d. block high voltage generated from lightning strikes."
        ],
        "correct": "a. minimize noise."
    },
    {
        "question": "26. (210) In an isolated ground (IG) receptacle, the ",
        "options": [
            "a. grounding pin is purposely insulated from the outlet box.",
            "b. IG will be bonded to other grounds in the immediate area.",
            "c. IG must have its own lightning arrester.",
            "d. IG must have its own driven ground rod."
        ],
        "correct": "a. grounding pin is purposely insulated from the outlet box."
    },
    {
        "question": "27. (211) What happens if a bare grounding wire touches the hot conductor terminal of a receptacle inside of a properly grounded outlet box? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Equipment plugged in the receptacle receives excessive current and overheats.",
            "b. The neutrals for the entire facility become hot conductors.",
            "c. The circuit breaker for that circuit trips.",
            "d. The outlet voltage is doubled."
        ],
        "correct": "c. The circuit breaker for that circuit trips."
    },
    {
        "question": "28. (211) Physical failure of grounding systems usually occurs in which portion of the system? ",
        "options": [
            "a. In the service panel.",
            "b. The ground electrode.",
            "c. Just above and below ground level.",
            "d. At the point where it attaches to the equipment."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Just above and below ground level."
    },
    {
        "question": "29. (211) In an interior wiring system with metallic conduit, through how many possible paths can return ground fault flow?",
        "options": [
            "a. Zero.",
            "b. One.",
            "c. Two.",
            "d. Three."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Two."
    },
    {
        "question": "30. (211) What test can you perform to ensure that the above grade components in a grounding system have a low resistance path to ground? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Earth resistance test.",
            "b. Vibroground test.",
            "c. Continuity test.",
            "d. Clamp-on test."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Continuity test."
    },
    {
        "question": "31. (212) What characteristics are the properties of good insulators?",
        "options": [
            "a. Clean dry surfaces in low humidity; can hold their charge.",
            "b. Clean dry surfaces in high humidity; can hold their charge.",
            "c. Contaminated surfaces in low humidity; can hold their charge.",
            "d. Clean dry surfaces in any humidity; permit leakage to take place."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Clean dry surfaces in low humidity; can hold their charge."
    },
    {
        "question": "32. (212) What minimum sparking voltage is generally accepted for the shortest measurable length of gap?",
        "options": [
            "a. 12 volts.",
            "b. 125 volts.",
            "c. 240 volts.",
            "d. 350 volts."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 350 volts."
    },
    {
        "question": "33. (213) Under proper conditions, approximately how much voltage can be charged up by a drop of liquid falling through the air? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 50 volts.",
            "b. 500 volts.",
            "c. 1,000 volts.",
            "d. 10,000 volts."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 10,000 volts."
    },
    {
        "question": "34. (213) At what voltage can a static charge ignite gasoline? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 120 volts.",
            "b. 750 volts.",
            "c. 1,500 volts.",
            "d. 7,500 volts."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 1,500 volts."
    },
    {
        "question": "35. (213) Unwanted electrical charges in hazardous areas are dissipated by using ",
        "options": [
            "a. rubber mats.",
            "b. air filtration systems.",
            "c. a continuous electrical path to ground.",
            "d. static elimination bars at all entry points."
        ],
        "correct": "c. a continuous electrical path to ground."
    },
    {
        "question": "36. (213) Which is not necessary for an adequate ground for static electricity? ",
        "options": [
            "a. High mechanical strength.",
            "b. Very low resistance.",
            "c. Secure connections.",
            "d. A continuous path."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Very low resistance."
    },
    {
        "question": "37. (213) Which size copper wire is used to bond conductive objects when they are not concealed or mechanically protected? ",
        "options": [
            "a. No. 16 American Wire Gauge (AWG).",
            "b. No. 12 AWG.",
            "c. No. 8 AWG.",
            "d. No. 6 AWG."
        ],
        "correct": "d. No. 6 AWG."
    },
    {
        "question": "38. (214) The type of ionic current that describes the rate of electron loss from earth is called ",
        "options": [
            "a. air-earth.",
            "b. air-water.",
            "c. sky-earth.",
            "d. sky-water."
        ],
        "correct": "a. air-earth."
    },
    {
        "question": "39. (214) The process of separating air molecules into positive ions and negative electrons is called ",
        "options": [
            "a. ionization.",
            "b. salinization.",
            "c. de-ionization.",
            "d. de-salinization."
        ],
        "correct": "a. ionization."
    },
    {
        "question": "40. (215) Lightning grounds are designed ",
        "options": [
            "a. to handle high voltages.",
            "b. to carry large currents.",
            "c. for high capacitance.",
            "d. for high impedance."
        ],
        "correct": "b. to carry large currents."
    },
    {
        "question": "41. (215) What size is the minimum for grounding conductors used for hazardous locations? ",
        "options": [
            "a. No. 6 American Wire Gauge (AWG).",
            "b. No. 4 AWG.",
            "c. No. 1/0 AWG.",
            "d. No. 4/0 AWG."
        ],
        "correct": "c. No. 1/0 AWG."
    },
    {
        "question": "42. (215) The maximum spacing, in feet, between air terminals is ",
        "options": [
            "a. 25.",
            "b. 50.",
            "c. 100.",
            "d. 150."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 25."
    },
    {
        "question": "43. (215) What number of inches is the minimum radius for lightning protection conductors bend? ",
        "options": [
            "a. One.",
            "b. Two.",
            "c. Four.",
            "d. Eight."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Eight."
    },
    {
        "question": "44. (216) Grounding of lightning protection systems should conform to ",
        "options": [
            "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 77.",
            "b. NFPA 78.",
            "c. NFPA 780.",
            "d. NFPA 802."
        ],
        "correct": "c. NFPA 780."
    },
    {
        "question": "45. (216) What size ground rods are used in a lightning protection system? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 8 feet in length, and 1/2-inch diameter.",
            "b. 8 feet in length, and 3/4-inch diameter.",
            "c. 10 feet in length, and 1/2-inch diameter.",
            "d. 10 feet in length, and 3/4-inch diameter."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 10 feet in length, and 3/4-inch diameter."
    },
    {
        "question": "46. (216) When ground rods are used with a loop conductor, how deep are ground rod tops driven?",
        "options": [
            "a. 6 inches below finished grade.",
            "b. 18 inches below finished grade.",
            "c. To same elevation as loop conductor below finished grade.",
            "d. To same elevation as the facility ground below finished grade."
        ],
        "correct": "c. To same elevation as loop conductor below finished grade."
    },
    {
        "question": "47. (216) What is the minimum size copper wire used to connect different grounding systems? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 14 American Wire Gauge (AWG).",
            "b. 6 AWG.",
            "c. 2 AWG.",
            "d. 1/0 AWG."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 6 AWG."
    },
    {
        "question": "48. (217) What number of feet must down conductors not exceed? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 25.",
            "b. 50.",
            "c. 100.",
            "d. 125."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 100."
    },
    {
        "question": "49. (217) How far into the ground must grounding rings be buried? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 10 inches.",
            "b. 15 inches.",
            "c. 30 inches.",
            "d. 45 inches."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 30 inches."
    },
    {
        "question": "50. (218) The ions that leave the metal and enter into the solution are ",
        "options": [
            "a. free electrons.",
            "b. anodes.",
            "c. positive.",
            "d. negative."
        ],
        "correct": "b. anodes."
    },
    {
        "question": "51. (219) How many basic ways can corrosion occur? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Two.",
            "b. Three.",
            "c. Four.",
            "d. Five."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Four."
    },
    {
        "question": "52. (219) Where does stray current corrosion cause greatest damage? ",
        "options": [
            "a. At midpoint between entry and exit of a structure. b. The bottom side of a structure.",
            "c. Where it enters a structure.",
            "d. Where it exits a structure."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Where it exits a structure."
    },
    {
        "question": "53. (220) How many ways can cathodic protection be achieved? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 2.",
            "b. 4.",
            "c. 6.",
            "d. 8."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 2."
    },
    {
        "question": "54. (220) At least how many inches of backfill should extend from each end of the anode? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 4.",
            "b. 8.",
            "c. 10.",
            "d. 12."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 12."
    },
    {
        "question": "55. (221) What purpose does the rectifier operational inspection serve?",
        "options": [
            "a. To determine the serviceability of all components required to impress current to the anodes of the impressed current system.",
            "b. To determine the unserviceability of some components required to impress current to the anodes of the impressed current system.",
            "c. To determine the reliability of all components required to impress current to the anodes of the impressed current system.",
            "d. To determine the compatibility of all components required to impress current to the anodes of the impressed current system."
        ],
        "correct": "a. To determine the serviceability of all components required to impress current to the anodes of the impressed current system."
    },
    {
        "question": "56. (221) How often should a structure be checked for depth of pitting?",
        "options": [
            "a. Every two years.",
            "b. Yearly.",
            "c. Semiannually.",
            "d. Monthly."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Every two years."
    },
    {
        "question": "57. (222) What voltage does a fire alarm system operate on, and what additional power source does the panel have? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 12 volts, direct current (VDC),backup circuit.",
            "b. 12VDC, battery backup.",
            "c. 24VDC, backup circuit.",
            "d. 24VDC, battery backup."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 24VDC, battery backup."
    },
    {
        "question": "58. (222) What is defined as a situation, environmental state, or equipment state of a fire alarm? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Alarm.",
            "b. Condition.",
            "c. Trouble.",
            "d. Situation."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Condition."
    },
    {
        "question": "59. (222) What situation would cause the fire department dispatch center to receive a supervisory alarm? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Open in a circuit.",
            "b. Ground on a circuit.",
            "c. Initiating device operates.",
            "d. Someone disables the fire suppression system."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Someone disables the fire suppression system."
    },
    {
        "question": "60. (223) Where in a facility will a pull station be located? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Next to fire alarm control panel.",
            "b. Near exits and in exit stairwells.",
            "c. Mechanical room.",
            "d. In every room."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Near exits and in exit stairwells."
    },
    {
        "question": "61. (223) What type of automatic detector is susceptible to false alarms in dusty environments? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Heat detector.",
            "b. Ion Smoke detector.",
            "c. Wavelength detector.",
            "d. Photoelectric Smoke detector."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Photoelectric Smoke detector."
    },
    {
        "question": "62. (223) What monitors the air in a heating, ventilation, and air conditioning (HVAC) system for signs of fire? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Heat detector.",
            "b. Flow detector.",
            "c. Duct detector.",
            "d. Smoke detector."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Duct detector."
    },
    {
        "question": "63. (223) Where is the end of line resistor in a Class A circuit? ",
        "options": [
            "a. In the middle of the circuit.",
            "b. At the end of the circuit.",
            "c. In the panel.",
            "d. Not used."
        ],
        "correct": "c. In the panel."
    },
    {
        "question": "64. (223) What is used in larger facilities to expand the notification appliance circuit (NAC)? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Initiating device circuit extender.",
            "b. Power amplifier.",
            "c. Booster panel.",
            "d. Amp panel."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Booster panel."
    },
    {
        "question": "65. (223) What is the polarity of a notification appliance circuit (NAC) that has been activated?",
        "options": [
            "a. Forward.",
            "b. Reverse.",
            "c. Alternating.",
            "d. None of the above."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Forward."
    },
    {
        "question": "66. (224) How is an addressable circuit supervised? ",
        "options": [
            "a. The detectors \"Talk\" to the fire alarm control panel (FACP).",
            "b. The FACP broadcasts messages to all the detectors.",
            "c. The detectors relay messages to the FACP.",
            "d. The same as in a conventional system"
        ],
        "correct": "a. The detectors \"Talk\" to the fire alarm control panel (FACP)."
    },
    {
        "question": "67. (224) How are addressable detectors and modules assigned an address? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Device address is set when they are manufactured.",
            "b. By turning two rotary switches on the device.",
            "c. Setting \"dip\" switches on the device.",
            "d. Using manufacturer software."
        ],
        "correct": "b. By turning two rotary switches on the device."
    },
    {
        "question": "68. (225) What commercial code specifies or mandates maintenance requirements for fire protection systems? ",
        "options": [
            "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 72.",
            "b. United Facilities Criteria (UFC) 3-601-02.",
            "c. NFPA 70.",
            "d. UFC 4-021-01."
        ],
        "correct": "a. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 72."
    },
    {
        "question": "69. (225) How often are devices normally calibrated? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Annually.",
            "b. Semi-annually.",
            "c. Every five years.",
            "d. Every two years."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Every five years."
    },
    {
        "question": "70. (226) Why do mass notification systems have priority over fire alarm systems? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Both systems function independently.",
            "b. Each condition is processed on a case by case basis.",
            "c. This is a false statement, fire alarm systems have priority.",
            "d. Perpetrators have been known to use the fire alarm system as a means of attack."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Perpetrators have been known to use the fire alarm system as a means of attack."
    },
    {
        "question": "71. (226) What color is the globe of a mass notification system (MNS) strobe in an Air Force facility? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Clear.",
            "b. Green.",
            "c. Red.",
            "d. Amber."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Amber."
    },
    {
        "question": "72. (226) What wattage is the maximum size of speaker used by an in-building mass notification system (MNS) without approval by the authority having jurisdiction (AHJ)? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 8 watts.",
            "b. 12 watts.",
            "c. 15 watts.",
            "d. 25 watts."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 15 watts."
    }
]